meltwater.com 2015-12-08

# Privacy Policy — Meltwater

At Meltwater, we know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and that is why we are committed to respecting your privacy and to helping protect the security of your information. In this Privacy Policy, we describe the information that we collect about you on this website (our “Site”), and how we use and disclose that information.

By visiting the Site or using any of our services available on our Site, you agree that your information will be handled as described in this Policy. If you purchase our Products, your use of those Products also will be governed by the Privacy Policy for Meltwater Products, available on the websites for the applicable Products. If there is any conflict between that policy and this one, the terms of that policy will govern.

Your use of our Site and services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use, including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. The Terms of Use are incorporated by reference into this Policy.

#### **What information do we collect about you and why?**

We collect information about you directly from you, automatically through your use of the Site or our services, and through third parties.

#### **_Information We Collect Directly From You_**

We collect information from you when you request information from us or otherwise interact with our Site and our services. The type of information that we collect from you depends on your particular interaction with our Site and may include, without limitation, your name, address, and email address, and any other information that you choose to provide to us.

#### **_Information We Collect Automatically_**

We and our third party service providers automatically collect information about you through the use of cookies and other tracking technologies (collectively, “cookies”), including:

We may collect, process and use the following information about you:

  * Details of your visits to our Site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, search activities as well as the page, content, software or resources that you access.
  * Your IP address, web addresses of the sites you arrive from and go to next and information about your connection, including your device’s browser, operating system, platform type and Internet connection speed. We use this information for operational and performance measurement purposes and to regionalize certain contents of the Site.
  * Details of transactions and orders, your history of correspondence with us, quote requests or inquiries or when you contact customer service or technical support.

Currently our Site does not recognize browser requests not to be tracked. You may adjust your browser settings so as not to accept cookies. Please see our Cookie Statement for additional information.

#### **_Information We Collect About You From Third Parties_**

We also may collect data from third party sources (such as contact information) as well as on behalf of our customers and at their direction. If we do so, we collect this information from publicly available third party sources.

## How we use your information

Information about our customers is an integral part of our business. We use your information, including your personal information, for the following purposes:

  * To provide our Site and services to you, to facilitate the features on our Site, to communicate with you about your use of our Site and Services, to respond to your inquiries, to manage your account, to send you information that you have requested, and for other customer service purposes.
  * For marketing and advertising purposes. For example, as permitted by applicable law, we may occasionally contact you by e-mail, postal mail, or telephone to provide you with information about goods or services that might be of interest to you.
  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer location customization, and personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using the Site or our Services.
  * To better understand how users access and use our Site and services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Site and Services and respond to user desires and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes.

## When We Disclose Your Information

We do not share your information with non-affiliated third parties for their own marketing purposes. We do share your information as follows:

  * **_Sales Channel Partners, Distributors, and Service Partners_** : we may provide information about you to carefully screened entities that work on our behalf, such as our sales channel partners, distributors or service partners, to market Meltwater products and services. Only trusted companies who require the use of said information for business purposes are given access to it.
  * **_To Our Affiliates_**. As permitted by applicable law, we may share your personal information with our affiliated entities. Those entities may market their products and services to you, but their use of your personal information will be governed by this privacy policy.
  * **_Service Providers_**. We may share your information with other third party service providers to assist us in bringing our Site and services to you, responding to your requests, and improving our Site and Services. We also may engage third parties to assist us in marketing our own products and services. 

We also may share your information in the following circumstances:

  * **_Business Transfers_**. If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the other company. We also may transfer our rights under any customer agreement we have with you.
  * **_In Response to Legal Process_**. We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena.
  * **_To Protect Us and Others_**. We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use or this Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.
  * **_Aggregate and De-Identified Information_**. We may share aggregate or de-identified information about users with third parties for marketing, advertising, research or similar purposes.
  * **_Legal Purposes_**. To enforce our Terms of Use; for example, to protect the security of our Site, as required by law or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights.

## Third-Party Ad Networks

We use third parties such as network advertisers to display advertisements on our Site, to assist us in displaying advertisements on third party websites, and to evaluate the success of our advertising campaigns. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to our Site as well as other websites. This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements by displaying ads for products and services in which you might be interested. Third party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. Please see our Cookie Statement for additional information.

You may opt-out of many third-party ad networks, including those operated by members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). For more information regarding this practice by NAI members and DAA members, and your choices regarding having this information used by these companies, including how to opt-out of third-party ad networks operated by NAI and DAA members, please visit their respective websites: in the United States: [www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp%E2%80%9D) (NAI) and www.aboutads.info/choices (DAA), and in Europe: [http://youronlinechoices.eu/](http://youronlinechoices.eu/%E2%80%9C).

## What Choices Do I Have Regarding Use of My Personal Information?

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to you. You may opt-out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the e-mail or by contacting us at privacy@www.meltwater.com. If you opt-out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you e-mails about your account or any services you have requested or received from us.

## Security

You should be aware that the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of the data transmitted to our Site—transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we have implemented security procedures and features to try to prevent unauthorized access. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

## Links

Our Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies. Please check their policies before you submit any personal data. Any subsequent changes to our privacy policy will be posted on this page.

Any subsequent changes to our privacy policy will be posted on this page.

## Reviewing and changing your personal information

Please contact Meltwater if you would like your personal information removed from our database. Please note that we will retain some of the information you may have requested us to remove for specific reasons, such as to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, and as required by law.

Furthermore, some information is never completely removed from our databases because of technical constraints and the fact that we regularly back up our systems. Therefore, not all of your personal information will ever be completely removed from our databases.

If you are a customer, in accordance with applicable law, you may modify personal information that you have submitted to us by logging into your account and updating your profile information.

## ￼Safe Harbor

Meltwater US Holdings Inc. complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information obtained from European Union member countries and Switzerland and has self-certified its adherence to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement with the United States Department of Commerce. To learn more about the safe harbor program, and to view Meltwater US Holdings Inc.’s certification, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor). If you believe that Meltwater US Holdings Inc. is misusing your information or violating the Safe Harbor principles, please contact [privacy@www.meltwater.com](mailto:privacy@www.meltwater.com).

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, Meltwater US Holdings commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact [privacy@www.meltwater.com](mailto:privacy@www.meltwater.com).

Meltwater US Holdings has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by (your company name), please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints) for more information and to file a complaint.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this policy or the use of your personal information, please contact us at [privacy@www.meltwater.com](mailto:privacy@www.meltwater.com).

￼￼

## Cookie Statement

At Meltwater, we know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and that is why we are committed to respecting your privacy and helping protect the security of your information. The purpose of this cookie statement (“Statement”) is to help you better understand how and why we gather, store and process information collected from you automatically through cookies and other tracking technologies (collectively, “cookies”) when you use a Meltwater website, including, [www.meltwater.com](https://www.meltwater.xn--com-9o0a/) (“Site”). In this Statement, we also identify your options regarding the use of cookies and the information collected through cookies.

Visiting or using this website with your browser settings adjusted to accept cookies tells us that you want to use our products and services and that you consent to our use of cookies and other technologies as described in this notice. Should you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@www.meltwater.com).

### What does this statement apply to?

This Statement covers the collection and use of personal information by Meltwater when a visitor browses [www.meltwater.com](https://www.meltwater.xn--com-9o0a/) (“Site”). This includes all related pages, any subscription-based features or services offered by Meltwater via the Site as well as the use of any of the Site’s related features and services. It does not apply to other online or offline Meltwater sites, products, services, nor does it apply to any third-party site that may be linked in our Site.

### What are Cookies?

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information that are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are sent back to the website at each subsequent visit or to any another website that recognizes them. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognize a user’s device.

Cookies perform lots of different jobs such as: allow you to navigate between pages efficiently, remember your preferences and generally improve your experience. Due to their core role of enhancing or enabling usability or site processes, disabling cookies may prevent you from using certain parts of this Site. The categories of cookies used on this Site are listed below.

### Why we collect information

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to deliver a smooth, efficient and personalized experience when on our website. This allows us to provide you with the information, services and features that are most likely to meet your needs.

We automatically track certain information about you, based upon your behavior on our Site. We use this information to conduct internal research on our user demographics, interests and behaviors, and to offer more personalized content.

The information we collect from you and about you is used as follows:

  * To ensure that content from our Site is presented as optimally as possible for you, your computer and your web browser.
  * To measure and improve the website’s performance and usability, its contents, services and features as well as to personalize your overall experience.
  * To send you information based on your relationship or transactions with us, notify you about changes to our products or services, provide customer support and respond to your inquiries.

## Cookies used on this website

Type | Name | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Session cookies | ASP.NET_SessionId | We use a session cookie to recognize you from page to page within the website, to remember you when you are logged-in or to enable services and features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. 

This cookie lasts for the duration of your visit. It is destroyed when you close the browser or navigate away from the Meltwater website.

By using our Site, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.

When these cookies are disabled, various functions of the site will be broken or unavailable.

For more information on session cookies and what they are used for, [click here](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/session-cookies-used-for.html).  
  
Performance Cookies | Google Analytics  
__utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmv  
__utmz | Performance cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, i.e., the pages you go to most often, and any error messages you receive. 

These cookies do not collect information that identifies you. The information these cookies collect is aggregated, therefore anonymous, and is only used to understand how the site is being used and identify problem areas to improve user experience.

You can find out more about Google’s privacy policy concerning its analytics service at [Google privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/analytics/privacyoverview.html). Google also offers a tool that allows you to opt-out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites and can be found [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  
  
Functionality Cookies | Persistent Cookies | We use persistent cookies to enable our Site to recognize you on subsequent visits, thus speeding up or enhancing your experience, as well as remember your settings and preferences, such as your user name, language, region and other customization options. 

They may also be used to provide services such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. Such cookies do not track your browsing activity on other websites.

By using our Site, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.

When these cookies are disabled, various functions of the Site will be broken or unavailable.  
  
Targeting Cookies | Marketo Cookies  
_mkto_trk  
_mkt_library  
_mkt_whitepapers | This Site uses an automation system provided by Marketo Inc., which uses cookies to recognize you as a unique user when you return to the site, and to track various data related to your website usage in order to provide custom content or services related to your specific interests. 

The cookies placed by the Marketo server are readable only by Marketo. For more information on Marketo cookies and what they are used for, [click here](http://www.marketo.com/trust/privacy.php).  
  
￼￼￼￼  

## Other cookie data collection that may be used on this Site

**Flash cookies/Local shared objects**. Adobe Flash Player is used to deliver a rich media experience. Where we use Macromedia Flash on our Site, a small Flash Cookie may be used. The purpose of using these cookies is to store your flash player preferences and enhance your browsing experience. Flash Cookies are stored on your computer like standard cookies, except that they are stored in a different location. For this reason, it is not always possible to block or manage Flash Cookies directly from your browser.

To manage or delete Flash Cookies, please visit [Adobe’s website]() for full information. Please note that some of the interactive tools will cease to work properly when Flash Cookies are disabled.

**Social buttons**. On many of the pages of our Site you will see “social buttons”. These enable users to share or bookmark web pages or access Meltwater content on these social media. These buttons include: Twitter, Google+, Facebook “Like”, LinkedIn “Share”, ShareThis and YouTube. You may also find other regional or language-specific social media buttons. By clicking on any of these buttons, the sites will register your action and may use that information.

To implement these buttons and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, scripts from domains outside of Meltwater must be used. You should be aware that when you are logged-in to the services of these sites (e.g., Google and Facebook), they are likely to be collecting information about your browsing habits, including when on the Meltwater Site, even if you do not click on a social button. Read the respective policies of each of these sites to see how they use your information and how to opt-out or delete such information.

The information we collect about you.

We may collect, process and use the following information about you:

  * Details of your visits to our Site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, search activities as well as the page, content, software or resources that you access.
  * Your IP address, web addresses of the sites you arrive from and go to next and information about your connection, including your device’s browser, operating system, platform type and Internet connection speed. We use this information for operational and performance measurement purposes and to regionalize certain contents of the Site.
  * Details of transactions and orders, your history of correspondence with us, quote requests or inquiries or when you contact customer service or technical support.

Information generated and collected automatically

We use web analytics tools to automatically store Site usage information, such as the origin, numbers and frequency of visitors to our Site and how they use its contents and components. This data is only used in the analytics tool aggregate and helps us figure out how to provide an optimal experience to as many users as possible.

When a user provides us with information that identifies him, such as when you fill a form on the site, we may store it in our marketing databases to personalize your relationship with Meltwater. We do this to recognize you and to gather data when you visit our Site; we may also do this with cookies (learn more in the section on cookies).

Some options are available to help you anonymously visit websites, including the possibility to set your web browser to block all cookies or to initiate an anonymous browsing session.

## How can your web browser control cookies

Currently, our Site does not recognize browser do-not-track signals. You have other means, however, in which to control cookies. All major browsers provide security controls for cookies. In general, they allow users to block all cookies, or block specific or third-party cookies. You may also activate the settings on your browser that allow you to refuse cookies. Unless you set your browser to refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log-on to our site.

The “help” portion of the toolbar in most browsers will provide information on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to tell the browser to inform you when you receive a new cookie or how to disable cookies altogether.

We strongly recommend that you accept cookies, because cookies enable you to take advantage of some of our Site’s features

## What can you do to control cookies collected on this Site

If you disagree with the use of cookies, you have the following options:

  * You can delete cookies after having visited the Site
  * You can browse the Site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” in Internet Explorer, “Private Browsing” in Firefox and Safari) 
  * You can set your browser’s security controls so that all or certain cookies are blocked
  * You can request that we delete any personal information that we collected—to do so, write us

## Conditions of use

If you decide to visit the Meltwater Site, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Cookie Statement.

## How to contact us for more information

We welcome all comments regarding this Statement. If you have questions related to our Cookie and Cookie Statement, or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us by sending an e-mail to [privacy@www.meltwater.com](mailto:privacy@www.meltwater.com%E2%80%9D).
